"I believe you will serve your school and community well by hiring Amy Hieber."

Amy D. Hieber

Certified Reading Specialist

Certified Elementary Teacher (K-8)

6954 Berkshire Drive Export, PA 15632.

•724-733-9010•

•amy.hieber@gmail.com

"I am constantly impressed with her ability to gently encourage the children while still maintaining her position of authority

in the classroom."

Personal Summary

Experienced educator offering a caring and creative approach to teaching. Classroom accountability in public, private, and parochial schools. Familiarity with urban, suburban, and rural community teaching. Practice in developing community programming and managing volunteer-based initiatives.

Experience

THE FIRST UNITED METHODIST PRESCHOOL- Murrysville, PA Three Year Old Teacher

2010-present

"Amy deeply cares for and values each students' uniqueness and individuality."

- Coordinated age appropriate instruction for 18-28 children.
 - Revamped curriculum for the three year old class based on monthly themes and student needs. Created lesson plans based on these themes.
 - Corresponded with parents and caregivers through a monthly newsletter.
 - Designed developmentally appropriate hands-on activities and games.
 - Incorporated family involvement in lesson planning.
 - Planned and scheduled enrichment activities such as field trips and guest speakers

"Amy has proven herself to be a dedicated and dependable teacher."

VOLUNTEER POSITIONS- Murrysville, PA and various communities

2003-present

- "Mother's Circle" Steering Committee, St. Barbara's Church, Harrison City, PA
- President of Manordale Farms Civic Association
- Deacon, Newlonsburg Presbyterian Church
- Vacation Bible School Planning Committee, Newlonsburg Presbyterian Church
- Sunday School Teacher, Newlonsburg Presbyterian Church
- Box Tops Coordinator, Heritage Elementary School, Franklin Regional SD
- Classroom Volunteer, Field Trip Volunteer, Heritage Elementary School
- Ruling Elder, Newlonsburg Presbyterian Church
- International mission trip to LaCroix, Haiti to aid in English instruction

"Her knowledge of early literacy has been a real asset to the program."

SYLVAN LEARNING CENTER- Westlake, OH Teacher/Tutor

2000-2002

- Created personal plans for student success
- Tutored students with a range of ages

"There is no doubt in my mind that she is an outstanding educator who would be an excellent addition to your school."

LAKEWOOD PUBLIC LIBRARY- Lakewood, OH Paraprofessional position as Children's Library Programmer

2000-2001

Organized, promoted, and presented children's programs featuring stories, activities, music, and crafts.

SAINT AGNES PARISH SCHOOL- Louisville, KY

1998-2000

- 3rd Grade Teacher
- Coordinated instruction of all subjects for 22 children. Contributor to winning The Blue Ribbon School of Excellence, a prestigious award in academia.
- Selected to be the Faculty Representative to the school board; responsible for sharing teacher concerns and communicating board activity.
- Developed and implemented weekly detailed instructional plans for 22 students in 6 subject areas.
- Coordinated student needs with curriculum requirements
- Created hands-on activities to reinforce subject matter.

JEFFERSON COUNTRY PUBLIC SCHOOLS- Louisville, KY

1995-1998

4th Grade Teacher

- 6th Grade Teacher
- Coordinated instruction for 20-40 students
- Team leader who coordinated teaching schedules with 3 other teachers to create consistent grade level instruction
- Created a weekly classroom newsletter for parents highlighting goals, accomplishments and reminders of upcoming tests and events
- Planned and scheduled enrichment activities, field trips, and guest speakers
- Created classroom activities focused on improving team work and strengthening interpersonal skills
- Maintained student portfolios to assess areas of need and track improvement

ANCHORAGE PUBLIC SCHOOL- Anchorage, KY

1994-1995

- Instructional Assistant
 - Aided and assisted a child with Tourette Syndrome
 - Modified instruction
 - Created and utilized behavior modification plans
 - Aided in motor skill development

Education

Masters in Education, 1994 Edinboro University of Pennsylvania

Bachelors of Science in Elementary Education, 1993 Edinboro University of Pennsylvania

Professional Membership

International Literacy Association